calendarpedia.com 2019-07-30

# Privacy Policy - Calendarpedia.com

**Our policy on your privacy**  
We recognize that privacy is important to you as visitor to and user of our website Calendarpedia.com. We also understand the concerns about the use of personal data. This page outlines the types of personal information we receive and collect when you use Calendarpedia.com, how we use it, and the steps we take to safeguard and protect this information. We hope this will enable you to make an informed decision about sharing personal information with us. Calendarpedia.com strives to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all our operations. Likewise, we are dedicated to protecting our visitors' privacy on our website. If you have any questions about this or any other issue, please [contact us](http://www.calendarpedia.com/contact.html).

**Personal Information**  
Calendarpedia.com collects personally identifiable information from visitors to this website only on a voluntary basis and only when a visitor [contacts us](http://www.calendarpedia.com/contact.html) via the contact form or by e-mail. The only personal information collected in the contact form is your name and e-mail address. Both of these pieces of information are voluntary, and you're not required to enter this information into the contact form in order to contact us (however, if you would like us to be able to reply to you, please give us your e-mail address). Calendarpedia.com will use personal information received from you for internal purposes only and will _never_ sell, rent, distribute, provide or give your information to any third party, nor will it be used in any way other than to respond to your enquiry and/or notify you of updates to Calendarpedia.com relating to your enquiry. We also collect each visitor's IP address, which helps us combat spam and fraud. We do not use IP addresses for any other purpose.

Any personally identifiable information that we may collect from you is held securely to prevent any unauthorised access and/or disclosure to third parties.

If we make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information, we will inform you by placing a notice on our site.

If you have provided us with personal information and would like to update or correct that information, or have the information we hold on you deleted from our records, please [contact us](http://www.calendarpedia.com/contact.html).

**Non-personal Information**  
We collect information about you that is not personally identifiable, such as web server data and your IP address. We use this information to track the movements of visitors around the site, to analyse trends, to administer and improve the site, and to understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site. Non-personally identifiable information may include the browser name, the type of computer, and technical information about your method of connecting to our site, such as the operating system and the Internet service provider you used, and other similar information. This data can not be assigned to specific persons for us. A merge of this data with other data sources is not performed, and the data is deleted after a statistical evaluation. This information is used solely by us and is not shared or passed on in any way.

**Use of Cookies and Web Beacons**  
We use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. Cookies are identifiers that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize the site's pages, a cookie enables Calendarpedia.com to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

Cookies are used on nearly all web sites. All web sites in the European Union that use cookies are legally obliged to inform about their use of cookies in a document such as this.

You can delete cookies stored on your computer at any time. Please visit [aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/) for more information.

A web beacon is a transparent image file used to monitor your journey around a single website or collection of sites. They are also referred to as web bugs and are commonly used by sites that hire third-party services to monitor traffic. They may be used in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of a website.

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being sent. Privacy software can be used to override web beacons. Taking either of these actions shouldn't cause a problem with your access to and use of Calendarpedia.com.

In the course of ads being served on our website, we may serve third-party advertisements that use cookies and web beacons in order to ascertain how many times you've seen a particular advertisement. No personally identifiable information you give us is provided to any third party for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information on our website.

Some third-party advertisements may be provided by Google, which uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google uses the DART cookie, which enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visits to this site and other sites on the Web. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

The search box on this website ("Search Box") is powered by Google Inc. ("Google"). You acknowledge and agree that Google's [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy.

**Refusing, removing and disabling cookies**  
You can set your browser to accept or refuse all cookies automatically, or notify you when a cookie is being requested. Taking this action should not cause a problem with the continued use of our site. Managing your cookies and cookie preferences must be done in your browser's options/preferences. Here is a list of guides on how to do this for a number of popular browsers:

**More information about cookies**  
To learn more about cookies, and find more information about blocking certain types of cookies, please visit the [ICO website Cookies page](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/).

**Use of Google Analytics**  
Calendarpedia.com uses Google Analytics to analyze the use of this website. Google Analytics collects demographic and interest data, and generates statistical and other information about website use, by means of cookies. These cookies are kept on your computer. We share this information with Google, which will store and use this information on its servers. Google's privacy policy is available at <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

Calendarpedia.com uses information from Google Analytics to track the number of visits to the website, browsers and operating systems. No personally identifiable information is obtained from these cookies. We use the information that Google Analytics generates relating to our website to create reports about the use of the site. These reports allow us to update the site and improve your usage of it.

If you do not wish your data to be collected via Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser extension/add-on available from Google's website at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Use of Statcounter**  
Statcounter is an online service which helps us to understand our visitors; for example, how visitors find our website, how long they spend on our site, which web pages they are most interested in etc. We use Statcounter because better understanding how visitors are interacting with our website helps us to improve the content, design and functionality of our site. This allows us to offer a better online experience to our visitors.

Statcounter uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on visitors and visitor activity on our website. This data includes:

  * Time and date of visit (this can help us to identify and plan for busy periods on our website)
  * IP address (this is a numerical label assigned to a device by an Internet Service Provider to enable the device to access the internet)
  * Browser and operating system (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the browsers/operating systems used to access our site)
  * Device information e.g. device type and screen size (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the devices used to access our site)
  * Referring data e.g. a search engine link (this can help us to understand which search engines are helping visitors to find our website)

Furthermore, when you visit our website a Statcounter cookie (called "is_unique") may be placed in your browser. This cookie is used only to determine whether you are a first-time or returning visitor and to estimate unique visits to the site.

You can learn more about cookies from StatCounter and set your browser to refuse same by clicking [here](http://statcounter.com/about/set-refusal-cookie/).

For further details, please see the [Statcounter privacy policy](https://statcounter.com/about/legal/#privacy).

**Use of third-party advertising**  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on this website, which supports the further development of this website. These companies use cookies and web beacons in their ads to ascertain how many times you've seen an advertisement. We share this information with these companies, but do not provide them with any personally identifiable information for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information from our website.

Some third-party advertisements are served by Google. Google's cookie enables it to serve ads to our visitors based on their visits to other sites on the Web. You may opt out of personalized ads by visiting Google's Ads Settings page at [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). Further information about how Google manages data in its ad products can be found at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites> and in Google's privacy policy at <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

For third-party advertising companies that serve ads on this website please see the following lists provided by our advertising partners [Google](http://www.calendarpedia.com/download/commonly-used-ad-technology-providers.xlsx "Commonly used ad techonology providers") and [Yieldlove](http://www.calendarpedia.com/download/yieldlove_privacy_policy_publisher_en.docx), with information on opting out. You may also opt out of personalized ads for over 130 different ad networks on YourAdChoices ([http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/)) and Your Online Choices ([http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)).

**Retargeting Ads and Tracking Pixels**  
Calendarpedia.com may use retargeting ads, which require the setting of cookies in your browser, and Facebook pixels to determine the effectiveness of some Facebook ad campaigns. You can change your Facebook ad settings [here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen).

**Use of Facebook, Twitter and Google+ buttons**  
These services are used for buttons that allow you to like/follow Calendarpedia.com on social networks. Cookies are used to allow you to use the buttons directly if you are already logged in to the individual services, and to collect statistics about visitor behaviour. Should you wish to prevent those platforms from collecting data, please view their individual policies by using the following links: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy) and [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/?hl=en).

**Children's Privacy Protection**  
This website is directed to adults; it is not intended for use by children without parental consent, particularly children under 16 years of age. We operate our site in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and Article 8 of the GDPR. We will never knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under 16 years of age. Children under that age must have permission from a parent or legal guardian before contacting us.

**Recommended Providers**  
Calendarpedia.com recommends and links to a number of products and services. However, we are not responsible and cannot be held liable in any way for anything that occurs should you visit these websites, and/or contact, enter into an agreement with, or make a purchase from them. We have no control over the privacy policies that may or may not exist on any of the websites we link to. We recommend that you review each site's privacy policy before disclosing any personal information on these sites.

**How You Can Correct or Remove Information**  
We provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of our commitment to protect your personal information. If you have submitted personal information through our website and would like that information deleted from our records or would like to update or correct that information, please [contact us](http://www.calendarpedia.com/contact.html).

**Updates and Effective Date**  
Calendarpedia.com may occasionally change or update this Privacy Policy. Any changes will be noted on this page. We therefore encourage you to check this page occasionally to ensure that you accept any changes or updates.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in March 2019.

**Agreeing to this Privacy Policy**  
If you do not agree to Calendarpedia.com's Privacy Policy as set out on this page, please do not use this site or any services offered by this site. Your explicit consent indicates acceptance of this privacy policy in its entirety.

Please also see our [Terms of Use](http://www.calendarpedia.com/terms-of-use.html). Thank you.
